# **NUR RAHMAWATI AYUKARYANA**

Driven by profound interest in material science and the pursuit of clean energy for a sustainable future, Ayu is a student and researcher in Applied Physics from Indonesia. She is a fast learner with high adaptability in diverse research teams including industry, governmental organization, and academia. While she takes pride in independency, she has a strong belief in the power of collaboration and teamwork to achieve the best result. New challenge and real impact are what motivates her to keep going.

Contact: <a href="mailto:s221175y@st.go.tuat.ac.jp">st.go.tuat.ac.jp</a>

### **EDUCATION**

Tokyo University of Agriculture and Technology (TUAT)Tokyo, JapanMaster's Student, Applied PhysicsOct. 2022 – Sept. 2024Institute of Technology Bandung (ITB)Bandung, IndonesiaStudent, Engineering Physics (minor: Material Processing)Aug. 2017 – April 2022Grade: Cum LaudeTokyo University of Agriculture and Technology (TUAT)Tokyo, JapanExchange Student, Applied PhysicsSept. 2019 – Dec. 2019

# **RESEARCH EXPERIENCE**

# **Superconducting Materials Laboratory at National Institute for Material Science (NIMS)**

Tsukuba, Japan

Sept. 2023 - Sept. 2024

Research Trainee – Supervisor: Dr. Akihiro Kikuchi, Prof. Hiroaki Kamakura

• Work on the fabrication & development of MgB<sub>2</sub> superconductor wire by rapid heating and quenching technique to accelerate industrial processes.

Yamamoto Lab at TUAT Tokyo, Japan

Graduate Researcher – Supervisor: A./Prof. Akiyasu Yamamoto

Oct. 2022 - Sept. 2024

- Conduct research on 122-type Fe-based superconductors, focusing on enhancing critical current density through metal addition, ball-milling, and high-pressure sintering.
- Carry out extensive material characterizations and superconducting properties testing.

# **ASEAN Centre for Energy**

Remote

Research Intern – Supervisor: Beni Suryadi, Akbar Dwi Wahyono, Suwanto

Jun. 2022 – Sept. 2022

• Contributed to energy-related research and stakeholder meetings within the ASEAN (Association of Southeast Asian Nations) region.

# Research School of Physics at Australian National University (ANU)

Remote

Visiting Research Student - Supervisor: Prof. Patrick Kluth, Dr. Christian Notthoff Jun. 2021 - Dec. 2022

• Performed simulations of swift-heavy synchrotron irradiated GaSb using phase field method.

# **Advanced Functional Material Lab at ITB**

Bandung, Indonesia

Research Assistant – Supervisor: Prof. Brian Yuliarto, Dr. Ganes Shukri

Dec. 2020 - April 2022

 Analyzed dopants effect to overcome Cu-Zn disorder in CZTS thin film solar cell by DFT (Density Functional Theory) approach.

## Research Centre for Physics at the Indonesian Institute of Sciences (LIPI)

Remote

Research Intern – Supervisor: Dr. Eddwi Hesky Hasdeo

Jun. 2020 – Aug. 2020

• Studied the realization of fault-tolerant quantum computer using Majorana fermion-based qubits.

# **R&D Physical Sciences Group at IHI Corporation**

Yokohama, Japan

Research Intern – Supervisor: Dr. Tatsuya Sodekoda

Dec. 2019 – Jan. 2020

• Examined the proper superconducting material for a bending magnet design in a synchrotron project.

# Yamamoto Lab at TUAT

Tokyo, Japan

Research Student – Supervisor: A/ Prof. Akiyasu Yamamoto

Oct. 2019 - Dec. 2019

• Fabricated PIT (Powder-In-Tube) MgB<sub>2</sub> superconductor with Na- and C-based dopants and investigated the microstructural and superconducting properties.

#### **PUBLICATION**

**N. R. Ayukaryana**, M. H. Fauzi, E. H. Hasdeo. 2021. The Quest and Hope of Majorana Zero Modes in Topological Superconductor for Fault-Tolerant Quantum Computing: An introductory Overview. *AIP Conference Proceedings* (Vol. 2382, No. 1, p. 020007). (DOI: 10.1063/5.0059974)

**N. R. Ayukaryana**, Y. Hasegawa, A. Yamamoto. 2023. Microstructural Investigation of Ag-added BaFe<sub>1.84</sub>Co<sub>0.16</sub>As<sub>2</sub> Bulk Superconductor. *Japan Society of Applied Physics (JSAP) 2023 Spring Meeting.* (Poster presentation)

# **PROJECT**

- 2023 LION-A Team. LION Corporation's Strategic Entry into the Indian Market. *Presented in the TUAT-Steinbeis University Joint Program Summer 2023 Cohort.*
- 2020 **N. R. Ayukaryana**, N. Abdillah, G. Shukri, B. Yuliarto. Study of Doping Impact on Suppressing Cu-Zn Disorders in CZTS Solar Cell Absorber Layer Bulk. *Bachelor thesis*.
- 2019 **N. R. Ayukaryana**, R. Tanaka, K. Nakanishi. A. Yamamoto. Na-doped and C-doped MgB<sub>2</sub> Superconductor Fabrication through PICT (Powder-In-Closed-Tube) Method. *Presented at the AIMS program 2019 closing ceremony.* (DOI: 10.13140/RG.2.2.22328.98561)
- 2019 A. M. Zahra, **N. R. Ayukaryana**, H. Yajun. MHAEROFILTER: Aerogel for Batik Wastewater Treatment. *Pitched at Hult Prize TUAT 2020 competition*.

### **HONOR AND AWARD**

- 2022 **MEXT Japanese Government Scholarship**, awarded full scholarship for master's degree study.
- 2021 **UCLQ Quantum Tech Summer School 2021**, selected by the UCL Quantum Science and Technology Institute to participate in the summer school.
- **2021 25<sup>th</sup> AINSE Winter School Scholarship**, selected by AINSE Councilor to learn nuclear technology and facilities available at ANSTO (Australian Nuclear Science Technology Organisation).
- **ANU FRTA (Australian National University Future Research Talent Award)**, awarded by ANU as one of the Indonesia's emerging research talents to develop research skills in ANU College of Sciences.
- 2019 **Student Representative Speech,** delivered at AIMS TUAT Exchange Program 2019 Closing Ceremony.
- Winner of Hult Prize at TUAT, best team in a business competition held by Hult Prize Foundation. (https://www.itb.ac.id/news/read/57379/home/a-student-of-itb-led-her-team-to-champion-the-hult-prize-on-campus-in-japan)
- 2019 **AIMS (ASEAN International Mobility Students) Scholarship**, full scholarship from the Indonesian Ministry of Research Technology and Higher Education for a multilateral exchange program.
- **2019 JASSO Scholarship for Short-Term Study in Japan**
- 2018 **Unggulan Kemendikbud Scholarship,** awarded for high school student with outstanding achievement to pursue higher education with full tuition fee coverage, thesis and living allowance funded by the Indonesian Ministry of Education and Culture.

### **VOLUNTEERING AND LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE**

# **Indonesian Student Association at TUAT (PPI Nokodai)**

Tokyo, Japan

• Lead the organization to provide support system for Indonesian students at TUAT.

# International Mobility Students Club (IMSC) of ITB

Bandung, Indonesia

Sept. 2023 - present

President

President

Mar. 2021 – April 2022

• Led the organization to achieve its goal of introducing international mobility for ITB students. (https://partnership.itb.ac.id/international-mobility-students-club-imsc/)

# **IBM Qiskit Documentation Localization Project**

Remote

Contributor

Sept. 2020 - Dec. 2021

• Translated the Qiskit documentation from English to Indonesian in a hope to help Indonesian students learning more about quantum computing. (https://crowdin.com/project/qiskit-docs)

# **Engineering Physics Student Association (HMFT) of ITB**

Bandung, Indonesia

Head of Professional Development Division

Mar. 2020 - Feb. 2021

• Led a team of 13 to establish programs related to professional development for HMFT fellows.